<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<protocol name="primary_selection">
  <copyright>
    Copyright © 2015 Red Hat

    Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a
    copy of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"),
    to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation
    the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense,
    and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the
    Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

    The above copyright notice and this permission notice (including the next
    paragraph) shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the
    Software.

    THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
    IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
    FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT.  IN NO EVENT SHALL
    THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
    LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING
    FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER
    DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.
  </copyright>

  <interface name="zwp_primary_selection_device_manager_v1" version="1">
    <description summary="X primary selection emulation">
      Provides the ability to have a primary selection buffer to match that of
      the X server. This allows users to select bodies of text, and then paste
      them in another buffer without having to do the initial paste.

      The primary buffer manager is in charge of handling client's requests to
      indicate that text has been selection, along with handling client's access
      to selected text.
    </description>

    <request name="create_primary_selection_source">
      <description summary="create a new primary selection source">
        Create a new primary selection source.
      </description>
      <arg name="id" type="new_id" interface="zwp_primary_selection_source_v1"/>
    </request>

    <request name="get_primary_selection_device">
      <description summary="primary selection device manager">
        Singleton global object that manages the zwp_primary_selection_device_v1
        objects for each wl_seat.
      </description>
      <arg name="id" type="new_id" interface="zwp_primary_selection_device_v1"/>
      <arg name="seat" type="object" interface="wl_seat"/>
    </request>
  </interface>

  <interface name="zwp_primary_selection_device_v1" version="1">
    <request name="selection_set">
      <description summary="set the primary selection">
        Set the current contents of the primary selection buffer. This clears
        anything which was previously held in the primary selection buffer.

        This request can only be used while the window is focused.
      </description>
      <arg name="source" type="object" interface="zwp_primary_selection_source_v1">
    </request>

    <event name="selection_offer">
      <description summary="primary selection buffer is ready for reading">
        Sent when the client has permission to read from the primary selection
        buffer.

        This event is sent whenever the client receives a middle click, and will
        be received by the client before the actual middle click event. While
        the compositor is free to bind this event to another input event (such
        as a keyboard shortcut), the client should always treat pastes from the
        primary selection as middle clicks. This is to ensure the behavior is
        identical to that of primary selection pasting in X.

        It is up to the client to decide whether or not it is appropriate to
        read from the primary buffer and paste it's contents.
      </description>
      <arg name="offer" type="new_id" interface="zwp_primary_selection_offer_v1">
    </event>
  </interface>

  <interface name="zwp_primary_selection_offer_v1" version="1">
    <description summary="offer to transfer primary selection contents">
      A wp_primary_selection_offer represents an offer to transfer the contents
      of the primary selection clipboard to the client. Similar to
      wl_data_offer, the offer also describes the different mime types that the
      data can be converted to and provides the mechanisms for transferring the
      data directly to the client.
    </description>

    <request name="receive">
      <description summary="request that the data is transferred">
        To transfer the contents of the primary selection clipboard, the client
        issues this request and indicates the mime type that it wants to
        receive. The transfer happens through the passed file descriptor
        (typically created with the pipe system call). The source client writes
        the data in the mime type representation requested and then closes the
        file descriptor.

        The receiving client reads from the read end of the pipe until EOF and
        closes its end, at which point the transfer is complete.
      </description>
      <arg name="mime_type" type="string"/>
      <arg name="fd" type="fd"/>
    </request>

    <request name="destroy">
      <description summary="destroy the primary selection offer">
        Destroy the primary selection offer.
      </description>
    </request>

    <event name="offer">
      <description summary="advertise offered mime type">
        Sent immediately after creating the wp_primary_selection_offer object.
        One event per offered mime type.
      </description>
      <arg name="mime_type" type="string"/>
    </event>
  </interface>

  <interface name="zwp_primary_selection_source_v1" version="1">
    <description summary="offer to replace the contents of the primary selection">
      Similar to the relationship between a wl_data_offer and a wl_data_source
      object, the wp_primary_selection_source object is the source side of
      wp_primary_selection_offer, it provides a way to describe the offered
      data and respond to requests to transfer the new contents of the primary
      selection clipboard.
    </description>

    <request name="offer">
      <description summary="add an offered mime type">
        This request adds a mime type to the set of mime types advertised to
        targets. Can be called several times to offer multiple types.
      </description>
      <arg name="mime_type" type="string"/>
    </request>

    <request name="destroy">
      <description summary="destroy the primary selection source">
        Destroy the primary selection source.
      </description>
    </request>

    <event name="send">
      <description summary="send the primary selection contents">
        Request for the current primary selection contents from the client.
        Send the specified mime type over the passed file descriptor, then
        close it.
      </description>
      <arg name="mime_type" type="string"/>
      <arg name="fd" type="fd"/>
    </event>

    <event name="cancelled">
      <description summary="request for primary selection contents was canceled">
        This primary selection source has been replaced by another primary
        selection source. The client should clean up and destroy this primary
        selection source.
      </description>
    </event>
  </interface>
</protocol>
